Curriculum Vitae - Rafael M. Pestano

Rafael Pestano

Version 1.0 March 13, 2015

Table of Contents

1
2
2
2
3
3
4
5
6
6
6
6
6
6
6
7
7

Software Engineer / Developer

I'm looking for a **Software Engineer/Developer position** based on **Java EE** platform and related technologies.

I would like to focus my work on coding/testing, deal with infrastructure (devops), prospecting new technologies, evangelizing and sharing knowledge with teammates and also community.

Rafael has a bachelor degree of Computer Science and is a Software Developer/Engineer since **2007**.

He is actually a software engineer at PROCERGS.

He is passionate about IT and Open Source so he contributes to Open Source projects in many ways.

Rafael attends and speaks at conferences on **Java EE**, like The Developers Conference and also give talks at local Jug.

He blogs about Java EE and related technologies on his personal blog.

He's mainly working with Java enterprise web related technologies for about 7 years, has experience with agile methodologies and strong background on testing.

Main interests

- Java EE development
- Open source
- · Agile methodologies
- Testing (junit/Arquillian/BDD)
- Continuous Delivery
- SOA / Microservices
- · Docker and containers related technologies
- Documentation (Asciidoctor)

Personal details

Name: Rafael Mauricio Pestano

WebSite / Social Media: blog / (GitHub) / (twitter)

Location: Porto Alegre, RS, Brazil

Professional Experience

Java EE Engineer / Developer at Procergs

August 2011 to Now (On going)

PROCERGS - Data processing company of the State of Rio Grande do Sul

Position

Software Engineer - Java EE - Agile - DevOps

- Create and maintain in house JavaEE 6+ based solutions for speed up development
- Part of a Technical team which supports 300+ developers
- Prospecting new technologies (R&D)
- Evangelizing good practice and disciplines of agile methodologies such as testing and continuous delivery
- Migration of legacy technology to service based architecture
- worked 3 years (2011-2014) in internal software factory using scrum

Used technologies

- JavaEE 6 stack:
 - JSF 2.1
 - 。 CDI 1.0
 - JPA 2.1 (Hibernate 4.x)
 - EJB 3.1
 - JaxRS and JaxWS
- Primefaces / Richfaces
- Arquillian / Cucumber / Selenium / Junit (tests)

- Asciidoctor (Documentation)
- Swagger (REST API)
- JBoss EAP 6 (application server)
- SVN
- OracleDB

Java Developer at AdvancedIt

November 2010 to August 2011 AdvancedIt - Intelligence in information technology

Position

Java Developer

Used technologies

- Spring 3.x
- Hibernate 3.x
- JSF 1.1
- Richfaces
- Maven
- OC4J and tomcat application servers
- Nexus
- MyEclipse IDE
- Jasper reports
- OracleDB

Java Developer at e-Core

April 2010 to November 2010 e-Core - Atlassian platinum partner

Position

Java Developer

- Worked customizing Atlassian Jira issue tracker for various clients
- Developed a JavaEE 5 JBoss Seam based web application

Used technologies

- JavaEE 5
- Hibernate 3.x
- JSF 1.2
- EJB 3
- Richfaces
- Jboss Seam
- Ant
- Jboss 5 application server
- Eclipse IDE
- mercurial
- Jasper reports
- MySql

Java trainee at JFRS

October 2008 to April 2010 JFRS - Justiça Federal

Position

Java Trainee

Research and Development of Java EE 5 and Google Web Toolkit applications.

Used technologies

- JavaEE 5 stack
- JPA (toplink)
- JSF 1.2

- EJB 3
- Richfaces
- Glassfish 3 application server
- Netbeans IDE
- svn
- Jasper reports
- MySql
- JaxWS (apache axis)

Technical Skills

Languages and Specifications

Java SE, Java EE (JSF, BV, JPA, EJB, CDI, Servlet, JSP), J2EE, JavaScript, XML, CSS, AsciiDoc

Application Servers

JBoss EAP 6, WildFly 8, Glassfish, Bea Weblogic and Apache Tomcat

Frameworks and Libraries

Arquillian, JBoss Forge, Apache DeltaSpike, Primefaces, Richfaces

OS

Linux (Ubuntu) and Windows

Databases

Oracle, Postgress, MySQL and HSQLDB

Software Engineering

SOA, DevOps, Design Patterns, Unit Testing, Integration Testing, BDD, Continuous Delivery

Tools

Eclipse, IntelliJ, Netbeans, Maven, JIRA, Redemine, Subversion, **Git**, Asciidoctor, JMeter, Jenkins, Sonar, Artifactory

Cloud

Openshift, travisci, codeship

Open Source

Contribute to projects

I contribute in a different ways (code, documentation, blog, forums, conference, experimenting and opening issues) to severals projects like Asciidoctor, Arquillian, JBoss Forge and Deltaspike.

Some of my open source activities can be found here:

- Github account: General activity
- Conventions framework: Academical homegrown framework I maintain for learning Java EE.

Technical Writing

Publications

Graduation Thesis

• Towards a Software Metric for OSGi - Quality analysis in modular applications.

Blog

I frequently write blog posts at rpestano.wordpress.com.

Conferences & Presentations

- TDC 2014, Porto Alegre, October 2014
 - Presented Enterprise testing using Arquillian
- Braziljs, Porto Alegre, August 2012

Languages Skills

- Portuguese : native language
- English: fluent (reading, writting); advanced (speaking)

Education

Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul, Porto Alegre, Brazil

UFRGS

2005-2014 - Bachelor Degree

Interests

- Sport: Football (soccer) and weight/strength Training
- TV Shows: The walking dead, Prison break
- New technologies, Open Source
- Family
- Beer
- Music